<Claude Müller/>

#Full Stack Senior Software Engineer

B.Sc. Hons. Computer Science (scheduled to complete 20??)

Hard-working, enthusiastic, self-made coding polyglot who has worked with various programming languages and leans towards low-level programming. Webapps, websites, APIs, Arduino projects and video games are just some of the projects he's worked on. Enjoys contemplating problems and the way things work, how to fix or improve upon them, then takes great pleasure in building a creative and robust solution. Loves to constantly learn and acquire any skill needed through dedication and self-application.

Work History

2021/05 - current

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

Paystack - Lagos, Nigeria (Remote)

- As a senior on Refunds and Reversals, designed and built the refunds and reversals micro-service.
- Increase the efficiency and reliability of refunds and reversals through the use of technologies like Kafka.
- Part of the Stability and Reliability team in charge of tackling the hard problems facing the rapid growth of Paystack.



2020/05 - 2020/05

Senior Software Engineer

SPAN Digital Innovation - San Francisco, USA & Cape Town, SA (Remote)

- Create solutions as a polyglot full stack software engineer, covering projects in Go, Scala, Java, JavaScript and Python.
- Using technologies such as Caddy, Akka, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka and Hadoop.





2019/04 - 2020/03

Full Stack Developer Consultant

Team Extension - Bucharest, Romania (Remote)

- Wrote server-side and client-side code for Laravel and PyroCMS projects using PHP (Laravel), HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Part of team that built Laravel-based CRM system as well as custom
 PyroCMS website a company in energy management.
- Used Git, Jira, CircleCI.



2019/01 - 2020/01

PHP and JavaScript Developer

Crayon - Johannesburg, Gauteng, SA (Remote)

- Rewrote recruitment webapp into full Laravel and JavaScript-based solution that caters to 37000+ users.
- Extended MVP to include various features including: integration with payment partner; webcam integration; custom filtering.
- Linux (CentOS) VPS administration.
- Used Git, Asana.



2016/10 - 2018/02

JavaScript Developer

Derivco - La Lucia, KwaZulu-Natal, SA

- Maintained and extended global online Bingo app servicing millions of players.
- Wrote custom TypeScript and JavaScript Angular modules.
- Integrated with .NET back-end via protocol buffers.
- Extended custom integration with PixiJS WebGL/Canvas renderer.
- Wrote integration and unit tests with Jasmine.
- Used SVN, Git, TFS.



2015/01 - 2016/09

CTO and Chief Software Developer

2013/08 - 2014/12 Full Stack Web Developer

Flint Studio - Morningside, Gauteng, SA

- Develop systems and integrations using PHP (Laravel, CakePHP and vanilla)
- Develop custom themes and websites using PHP and WordPress.
- Work closely with designers to implement custom designs as per client spec.



2012/07 - 2013/07

Full Stack PHP and JavaScript Developer

Team Extension - Faerie Glen, Gauteng, SA

- Rewrote internal and client-facing web systems from Perl into PHP (Codelgniter) and JavaScript.
- Built mobile app for Android (native), iOS (native) and BlackBerry (PhoneGap).
- Built email campaign management utilities in Python.
- Linux administration (CentOS).



2010/01 - 2012/06

Owner/Web Designer/Web Developer

dragonFli designs - Benoni, Gauteng, SA

- Built websites and systems for various clients in PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS from scratch.
- Maintained and installed networks, workstations, servers and backup solutions.



Education

Tertiary

2022 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University Of The People - Pasadena (Distance)

2004 A+ Hardware and Software

2017/09	How to Program Games: Tile Classics in JS for HTML5 Canvas # Udemy
2020/08	Lightbend Scala Language Professional - Level 2 ** Lightbend
2020/08	Learn How To Code: Google's Go (golang) Programming Language *
2020/05	Go: The Complete Developer's Guide (Golang) * Udemy
2020/04	Python for Everybody Specialization * Coursera
2020/04	Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python ** Coursera
2020/04	Python for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) ** Coursera
2020/04	Python Data Structures # Coursera
2020/04	Using Databases with Python # Coursera
2020/04	Using Python to Access Web Data *

Coursera